Once upon a time, in a peaceful sunny meadow, there was a peacock.
Oh, he had the most beautiful feathers you've ever seen.
So colorful, so shiny, they look like magic rainbows.
Wush!
The soft wind blew, making his feathers shimmer as he stood by the pond, staring at his
reflection.
He loved to look at himself.
Ah, he sighed, no one in the world is as beautiful as me.
One day, a little sparrow flew by.
Flap, flap, flap.
She landed gently on a branch nearby and chirped.
Hello, peacock.
Your feathers are so pretty today.
The peacock puffed up his chest and spread his tail wide.
Ssh!
Of course they are, he said, smiling proudly.
No one is as beautiful as me.
The sparrow tilted her tidy head and smiled.
That may be true, she said.
Her voice kind and cheerful.
But beauty isn't everything, you know.
Can you sing as sweetly as I can?
The peacock chuckled.
Ha, why would I need to sing when my feathers are this perfect?
The sparrow giggled, flapping her little wings.
Sometimes peacock, being able to do other things can be just as special.
Suddenly, the sky dot darker.
Wush!
A shadow crept across the meadow.
A fox, quiet and sneaky, was creeping closer.
Russell, Russell.
His sharp eyes locked on a peacock.
The animals in the meadow froze for a moment, then ran.
The sparrow flew up up into the trees.
Not flap, flap, she tripped safely from a high branch.
But the peacock, oh the poor peacock, his big, heavy tail made it hard to fly.
He ran in circles, his bright feathers dragging behind him.
Swish, swish, swish!
Help!
He squawked.
His voice loud and frightened.
The fox pounced.
Wush!
But just before he could catch the peacock, a farmer came running waving a stick.
Shoo, shoe fox he shouted and the fox ran away into the woods.
The peacock still shaking found the sparrow sitting safely in her tree.
You were right, he said softly, his voice trembling.
My feathers are so pretty, but they didn't help me when I needed to get away.
The sparrow chirped gently.
It's okay, peacock.
Your feathers are beautiful, and that's special.
But it's also good to see what others can do.
Everyone has their own strengths.
The peacock nodded slowly, thinking about her words.
From that day on, he wasn't just proud of his feathers.
He learned to see how amazing other animals could be, too.
Moral.
Everyone is special in their own way, and we should appreciate each other's talents.
And now, close your eyes, little one.
Imagine the soft rustle of feathers, the gentle chirping of birds and the peaceful meadow
as you drift off to sleep.
Good night.
Shhh.